Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/pwarier (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Analytics
Predictive Analytics
Predictive Modeling

Publications

Commerce System and Method of Learning Consumer Behavior Based on Prior and Current Transactions

Dynamic Decision Support for Regional LTL carriers

Patents

System and method for transaction log cleansing and aggregation

Commerce System and Method of Learning Consumer Behavior Based on Prior and Current Transactions

System and method of model forecasting based on supply and demand

Prashant Warier

Co Founder & CEO at Qure.ai Mumbai

Summary

Prashant is an expert in the field of Artificial Intelligence and Deep learning. He has architected and commercialized several data science solutions in his 19 year career. He is also a prolific researcher, author, and speaker on topics related to data science and machine learning. He is passionate about using deep learning to make healthcare affordable and accessible.

Experience

Qure.ai Co Founder & CEO January 2016 - Present (4 years 8 months) Mumbai Area, India

Making healthcare accessible and affordable using deep learning.

At Qure.ai, we use deep learning to interpret CT Scans, X-Rays and MRIs and create automated diagnostic reports. This will help radiologists make faster and more accurate decisions in developed countries and provide automated radiology support to physicians in rural areas, where radiologists are typically not available.

Fractal Analytics
Chief Data Scientist
October 2015 - January 2016 (4 months)
Mumbai Area, India

Evangelize artificial intelligence and machine learning, build a world-class data science team and help our Fortune 500 clients adopt data science within their businesses.

Imagna Analytics
Co-Founder and CEO
November 2012 - October 2015 (3 years)
Mumbai Area, India

Imagna helps companies target their customers better through the power of Artificial Intelligence. Imagna's AdPersonix platform helps e-commerce

companies unify multiple data sources (such as web, mobile etc.) and create a single profile and context for each customer. In combination with advanced machine learning technology, the customer profile and context can then be used to market to each customer individually using perfectly tailored display advertising or personalized E-mail, SMS and app notifications.

Imagna was acquired by Fractal Analytics in Oct 2015.

Fractal Analytics
1 year 6 months

Vice President June 2012 - July 2012 (2 months)

Led the retail practice and contributed to the architecture and development of Customer Genomics and systematic experimentation solutions.

Director, Optimization Services and Solution Development February 2011 - July 2012 (1 year 6 months)

Responsible for the Retail client portfolio and for solution development across domains. Responsible for the development of a patent-pending technology for labeling a customer on various Customer DNA attributes based upon a learning algorithm which runs against the past transactions of the customer. Such a Customer DNA profile can be used to target individual customers and give customized email and Point- of-Sale offers to each customer.

SAP

Senior Research Scientist February 2007 - April 2011 (4 years 3 months) Scottsdale, AZ

Architected, developed and delivered data science solutions in Retail and Consumer Packaged Goods. Contributed towards building a team of data science leaders across US, Germany, and Romania. Developed and implemented a patent-pending Markdown Optimization solution for the Fashion industry. Developed solutions for Demand modeling, Key value item analysis and Assortment Rationalization among others.

Georgia Tech

Doctoral student and Graduate Research Assistant August 2003 - December 2006 (3 years 5 months)

Developed solutions which optimize linehaul operations for trucking networks. The optimization techniques focused on three major areas – Freight Routing

(how a specific shipment should be optimally routed from origin to destination in a very large trucking network), Load Planning (optimal strategy for packing shipments into truckloads to achieve maximum fill rates) and Driver Assignment (optimally assigning drivers with their DoT specified and personal constraints to these truckloads).

ORTEC

Research Scientist Intern May 2003 - August 2003 (4 months)

Education

Georgia Institute of Technology

Certificate in Engineering Entrepreneurship, Entrepreneurship/Entrepreneurial Studies · (2014 - 2016)

Georgia Institute of Technology

PhD, Industrial and Systems Engineering · (2001 - 2006)

Georgia Institute of Technology

Master of Science (MS), Operations Research · (2001 - 2003)

Indian Institute of Technology, Delhi

B Tech, Manufacturing Science and Engineering · (1997 - 2001)